# Ian De Bie

18102 San Gabriel Ave, Cerritos, CA 90703

Phone: 714.273.8994 • Email: idebie@wgu.edu • Profiles: in



# **Software Engineer**

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Recent college graduate with a BS in Computer Science and nearly 30 years of various work experience. Seeking to leverage acquired academic knowledge and background to effectively transition to a new career as a software engineer. A dedicated worker, proven quick learner, and problem solver that is eager to contribute to the company's overall growth and focus of the customer experience.

### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, December 2019

Western Governors University, Salt Lake City, Utah

• Excellence Award - For exemplary work in the Introduction to Artificial Intelligence

#### COURSEWORK

- Calculus I
- Software Engineering
- Computer Architecture
- Technical Communication
- Structured Query Language
- Software Quality Assurance
- Discrete Mathematics I & II
- Web Development Foundation

- Scripting and Programming Found. & Appl.
- Data Management Foundation & Application
- Software I & II Advanced Java Concepts
- Introduction to Artificial Intelligence
- Data Structures and Algorithms, I & II
- Business of IT Project Management
- Network and Security Foundation
- Operating Systems for Programmers

### **SKILLS**



Java

PHP

Javascript

SQL

HTML

CSS

#### **PROJECTS**

Computer Science Capstone, (December 2019). Created web app containing login, dashboard, and several charts and graphs displaying prediction model and data set for diagnosis of heart disease. Technologies used were Django for the framework, Bootstrap and jQuery for styling, and multiple Python libraries to create the predictive model and data visualizations. Libraries such as pandas, seaborn, numpy, matplotlib, sklearn, and dash were all involved in the project. Deployed on Heroku with these login credentials (username: admin, password: CAPstone)

Software II Project, (August 2019). Created an appointment app with a login that can add, update, and delete customer records and appointments, along with a calendar feature built with JavaFX components. Project built with Java using NetBeans IDE and Scenebuilder for the frontend and MySQL for the backend.

Recipe web app and Personal website. Personal side projects that were built with PHP using the Laravel framework and Postgresql that were deployed on Heroku. Several other personal project repositories are also located on my Github profile.

#### CERTIFICATIONS

Oracle Database SQL Certified Associate 1Z0-071, (10/28/2019) CompTIA Project+, (5/2/2019) CIW Site Development Associate, (2/4/2019) Axelos ITIL Foundation Cert, (10/18/2019)

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Ingram Micro, Inc •** Irvine, CA (November 2011 – April 2019)

Accounting Manager (July 2015 - April 2019)

- Promoted by demonstrating core competencies and vast knowledge of company operations impacting our department
- Managed over \$3 billion in receivables per year for special pricing programs
- Used Python to create automation scripts to retrieve online reports
- Received recognition for creating various Excel templates using VBA
- Responsible for solving daily escalations from internal and external customers
- Worked extensively with SQL developers designing in-house application

Senior Accountant (August 2013 – June 2015)

 Promoted after being recognized for personally maintaining \$0 aging over 90 days on over \$500 million in special pricing program receivables annually

Accountant II (November 2011 – July 2013)

- Established and cultivated relationships with our vendors driving timely resolution of outstanding receivables
- Utilized VBA and SQL to improve process efficiencies

# **Insight** • Tempe, AZ (January 2009 – October 2011)

Senior Analyst (April 2010 – October 2011)

- Promoted for managing the largest vendor program with lowest open aging Analyst (January 2009 March 2010)
  - Exceeded expectations for goals each year for write-off and aging metrics

# **Cashcall** • Anaheim, CA (2005 - 2008)

Production Manager (2007 - 2008)

 Promoted due to ability to motivate the team and assist customers, and had a high level of knowledge of the loan product programs

Loan Agent (2005 - 2007)

Won multiple sales contests receiving over \$50K in bonus commissions

## Potter Roemer • Santa Ana, CA (1999 - 2005)

Accounting Manager (2003 – 2005)

- Promoted based on exemplary performance of prior duties
- Managed AP, AR, and payroll teams, Cost and Staff Accountants

Cost Accountant (2002 - 2003)

- Promoted after demonstrating competencies in analysis and Excel
- Responsible for creating product bill of materials and physical inventory
- Prepared budget and forecast reporting in Excel

Staff Accountant (1999 – 2001)

- Prepared financial statements, sales/use tax returns, bank reconciliations
- Received recognition for reconciling over 12 months of unreconciled accounts

### Fisher Service Company • Paramount, CA (1996 - 1999)

Payroll Administrator (1998 - 1999)

- Promoted due to mastery of AP position by being efficient and accurate Accounts Payable (1996 1998)
  - Issue payments for approved purchase orders and review AP GL entries

# Enterprise Rent-A-Car • Carson, CA (1993 - 1996)

Leasing Accountant (1995 - 1996)

- Promoted based on attention to detail in GL by catching erroneous entries Accountant I (1993 1995)
  - General Ledger analysis and reporting

### **UPS United Parcel Service** • Cerritos, CA (1992 - 1993)

Pre-loader Package Handler (1992 - 1993)

Won multiple employee awards for speed and accuracy of loading trucks